Um... Satou?
&rlm;"ساتو"؟
What's this "important matter" you wanted to talk about?
&rlm;ما هي هذه "المسألة الهامة" &rlm;التي أردت التحدث عنها؟
Just get in.
&rlm;أدخل فحسب.
Uh... Okay.
&rlm;حسناً.
Hey, wait a minute. This seems awfully familiar.
&rlm;مهلاً، انتظر لحظة. &rlm;هذا يبدو مألوفاً على نحو مرعب.
As I recall, when I opened the door that time...
&rlm;كما أتذكر، حين فتحت الباب ذلك الوقت...
I got you! I got you good!
&rlm;خدعتك! &rlm;خدعتك جيداً!
She thought it was the most hilarious thing ever.
&rlm;ظنت أنه أكثر شيء &rlm;مضحك مطلقاً.
Okay, I'll fall for it again today, hook, line and sinker.
&rlm;حسناً، سأنخدع اليوم مجدداً، &rlm;خطاف وسلك وثقالة.
Come on, give the pranks a rest!
&rlm;بربك، توقفي عن المقالب!
Huh?
&rlm;ماذا؟
What are you doing?
&rlm;ماذا تفعل؟
Oh, um... I assumed you were playing another practical joke.
&rlm;أفترضت أنك كنت تقومين بمقلب آخر.
I said this was important, didn't I?
&rlm;قلت إن الأمر مهماً، أليس كذلك؟
That's what you said last time, and then you pulled a prank on me.
&rlm;هذا ما قلته المرة الماضية، &rlm;ثم قمت بمقلب بي.
- Listen... - Yes?
&rlm;- استمع... &rlm;- أجل؟
Can't you tell what it is?
&rlm;ألا يمكنك أن تعرف ما هذا؟
Can't I tell what what is?
&rlm;ألا يمكنني أن أعرف ما هذا؟
All I can tell is that you're as lovely as ever–
&rlm;كل ما يمكنني معرفته هو أنك &rlm;جميلة كالمعتاد...
Quit being an idiot!
&rlm;توقف عن التصرف بحماقة!
Come on, just tell me what it is!
&rlm;بربك، قولي لي ما هو!
I'm missing my you-know-what.
&rlm;أفوت ما تعرفه الخاص بي.
Oh? You missed it?
&rlm;فوته؟
Missed?! You don't mean–
&rlm;فوت؟ لا تعني...
It's embarrassing, so don't tell anyone, got it?
&rlm;الأمر محرج، لذا لا تخبر أحداً، فهمت؟
O-Of course not!
&rlm;لن أفعل بالطبع!
What am I going to do? Someone's going to have to take responsibility.
&rlm;ماذا سأفعل؟ يجب على شخص ما &rlm;أن يتحمل المسؤولية.
I-I'll do right by you.
&rlm;سأحسن التصرف معك.
Takagi...
&rlm;"تاكاغي"...
Hang on... In cases of marriage between police officers,
&rlm;انتظر... في حالات الزواج &rlm;بين ضباط الشرطة.
to say nothing of two officers in the same precinct,
&rlm;ناهيك عن ضابطين بنفس المنطقة.
given the possibility of issues arising from a married couple working together,
&rlm;نظراً لإمكانية ظهور مشاكل من &rlm;عمل الأزواج معاً.
one of them is supposed to transfer out.
&rlm;يجب أن ينتقل أحدهم.
Satou is the belle of Division 1, so if I cause her to transfer out...
&rlm;"ساتو" هي حسناء القسم الأول، &rlm;لذا إن تسببت في نقلها منه...
there's no telling what hell the senior detectives will put me through.
&rlm;من المستحيل معرفة ما سيفعله بي &rlm;كبار المحققين.
So I'll have to transfer to some other precinct.
&rlm;لذا يجب أن أنتقل لمنطقة أخرى.
No, I could resign and be a stay-at-home dad.
&rlm;كلا، يمكنني أن أستقيل وأكون والداً رب منزل.
Understood!
&rlm;مفهوم!
We're on our way.
&rlm;نحن في الطريق.
We got a tip that a suspect we're after was spotted in Beika Town.
&rlm;حصلنا على معلومة أن المشتبه به الذي نلاحقه &rlm;رصد في مدينة "بيكا".
We're going to check it out.
&rlm;سنذهب للتحقق من الأمر.
S-Sure!
&rlm;بالتأكيد!
-M-Miwako is having a baby? -What happy news!
&rlm;- سترزق "ميواكو" بطفل؟ &rlm;- يا لها من أخبار سعيدة!
A chic and dashing detective show that holds up under the blazing sun!
&rlm;عرض محققة أنيقة وذكية &rlm;صامدة تحت الشمس الحارقة!
Will Satou finally profess her feelings to Takagi?
&rlm;هل ستفصح "ساتو" أخيراً عن &rlm;مشاعرها لـ"تاكاغي"؟
A perfect alibi! A mystery written in the language of flowers!
&rlm;حجة غياب مثالية! سر مكتوب بلغة الزهور!
Always determining the one truth with the body of a child and the mind of an adult,
&rlm;يحدد دائماً الحقيقة الواحدة بجسد طفل &rlm;وعقل راشد.
his name is Detective Conan!
&rlm;اسمه المحقق "كونان"!
Metropolitan Police Detective Love Story (Confessions)
&rlm;قصة حب محقق شرطة العاصمة "اعترافات"
Come on, all three of you are yawning?
&rlm;بربكم، ثلاثتكم تتثاءبون؟
What are you, Haibara?
&rlm;أين أنت يا "هايبارا"؟
Well, excuse me for yawning a lot.
&rlm;حسناً، عفواً لأنني أتثاءب كثيراً.
We can't help it!
&rlm;لا يمكننا منع أنفسنا!
Titan Hunter just came out, and it's too much fun!
&rlm;خرج العملاق الصياد للتو، &rlm;والأمر ممتع بشدة!
We all got sucked into it.
&rlm;انغمسنا بها جميعاً.
Sheesh, you're wasting your precious summer vacation playing some game?
&rlm;اللعنة، تضيعون عطلتكم الصيفية الثمينة &rlm;بلعب لعبة ما؟
Oh, right! I got my daddy to help me and I made it to rank 5!
&rlm;صحيح! جعلت والدي يساعدني &rlm;ووصلت للمرتبة الـ5!
- Seriously? - I keep getting eaten by the blue titan!
&rlm;- جدياً؟ &rlm;- يستمر العملاق الأزرق بأكلي!
What kind of game is this?
&rlm;ما نوع هذه اللعبة؟
From what I hear, it's a roleplaying game
&rlm;مما أسمعه، هي لعبة أدوار
where you protect your castle from a race of attacking titans.
&rlm;حيث تحمي قلعتك من سلالة من &rlm;العمالقة الذين يهاجمونك.
Now that you mention it, the strategy guide goes on sale today, doesn't it?
&rlm;بعد أن ذكرت الأمر، دليل الإستراتيجيات &rlm;يباع بتخفيض اليوم، أليس كذلك؟
Wow, right!
&rlm;بلى!
Hey, do you think they have it in that mini-mart over there?
&rlm;هل تعتقد أنهم يبيعونه بهذا السوق &rlm;المركزي الصغير هناك؟
Let's go see!
&rlm;لنذهب لنر.
Hey!
&rlm;مهلاً!
I thought we were going to go play soccer in the park!
&rlm;ظننت أننا سنذهب للعب كرة القدم بالحديقة!
I guess not.
&rlm;لا أعتقد ذلك.
Damn it...
&rlm;تباً...
Was there an accident there?
&rlm;هل وقع حادث هناك؟
And those flowers...
&rlm;وهذه الزهور...
I think those are called false dragonheads.
&rlm;أعتقد أن اسمها "فولس دراغونهيد".
They signify...
&rlm;إنها تدل على...
Edogawa.
&rlm;"إيدوغاوا".
What are you doing? Keep up.
&rlm;ماذا تفعل؟ تحرك.
Oh. Sure.
&rlm;بالتأكيد.
That sure was a surprise.
&rlm;كانت هذه مفاجأة بالتأكيد.
I can't believe a total stranger looked so much like our suspect.
&rlm;لا أصدق أنه غريب بدا بشدة مثل المشتبه به &rlm;الخاص بنا.
That's for sure.
&rlm;هذا مؤكد.
It's a little late, but do you want to grab lunch somewhere around here?
&rlm;تأخر الوقت قليلاً، لكن هل تريد &rlm;جلب غداء من مكان ما هنا؟
Oh, sure!
&rlm;بالتأكيد!
How about pickles and ice cream or something?
&rlm;ماذا عن مخلل ومثلجات أو شيء؟
Huh? Why would I want that?
&rlm;لم قد أريد هذا؟
Whoa, awesome!
&rlm;مذهل!
- This says it's called the Haouken! - It's so cool!
&rlm;- مكتوب أن هذا اسمه "هاوكن"! &rlm;- إنه رائع جداً!
It says its ATK stat is over 10,000, and is the only blade feared by the titans!
&rlm;ويقول إن إحصائية الهجوم أكثر من 10 آلاف &rlm;وهو السيف الوحيد الذي يخاف منه العمالقة!
It's B&amp;W, so you can't tell what it really looks like, though.
&rlm;إنه بالأبيض والأسود، لذا لا يمكنك &rlm;معرفة كيف يبدو حقاً رغم هذا.
It says here that you can only get it if you're rank 8
&rlm;مكتوب هنا أنه بإمكانك الحصول عليه &rlm;إن كنت بالمرتبة الـ8 فحسب
and defeat a big-ass, red titan!
&rlm;وهزيمة عملاق أحمر كبير!
I won't be getting it anytime soon...
&rlm;لن أحصل عليه بأي وقت قريباً...
Oh, I have that sword.
&rlm;لدي هذا السيف.
Its hilt is shiny and gold, and the design on the blade is red!
&rlm;مقبضه لامع وذهبي، &rlm;والتصميم على النصل أحمر!
Noriya Makabe (7) 1st-year Grade School Student
&rlm;"(نوريا مكابي)، (7) &rlm;طالب بالعام الأول من المدرسة الابتدائية."
It seems like you still need to get a bunch of buff items
&rlm;يبدو أنك لا تزال بحاجة لجلب &rlm;حفنة من الأشياء القوية
to level up the sword afterwards, though.
&rlm;للوصول لمستوى السيف بعد ذلك رغم هذا.
Oh, wow! You made rank 8, then?
&rlm;وصلت للمرتبة الـ8 إذن؟
Yep!
&rlm;أجل!
Hang on, aren't you in the class next to ours?
&rlm;انتظر، ألست بالصف المجاور لصفنا؟
You aren't lying to make yourself sound cool, are you?
&rlm;أنت لا تكذب لتبدو رائعاً، أليس كذلك؟
I'm not lying!
&rlm;أنا لا أكذب!
Right, big brother Toshinari?
&rlm;أليس كذلك أيها الأخ الأكبر "توشيناري"؟
That's right.
&rlm;هذا صحيح.
You worked hard for it.
&rlm;عملت بجد من أجل ذلك.
Huh? That's the guy from the street...
&rlm;هذا هو الرجل من الشارع...
If you really got the Haouken, I'd sure love to see it!
&rlm;إن كان معك الـ"هاوكن" حقاً، &rlm;فأود أن أراه بالتأكيد!
-Me, too!
&rlm;- وأنا أيضاً!
Want to come over to Toshinari's place, then?
&rlm;هل تريدون المجيء لمنزل "توشيناري" إذن؟
It's okay, isn't it?
&rlm;ليست مشكلة، أليس كذلك؟
Toshinari Shiga (25) Graduate Student
&rlm;"(توشيناري شيغا)، (25) &rlm;طالب دراسات عليا"
Wait for me in the car, then. I'll go pay our bill.
&rlm;انتظرني في السيارة إذن. &rlm;سأذهب لدفع فاتورتنا.
That comes to 1,350 yen.
&rlm;الإجمالي 1350 يناً.
Put it on my card, please.
&rlm;اسحبيهم من بطاقتي رجاءً.
- Of course. Number of payments? - One-time charge.
&rlm;- بالطبع. عدد الدفعات؟ &rlm;- سداد بمرة واحدة.
Of course.
&rlm;بالطبع.
He drives an import and has a platinum card...
&rlm;يقود سيارة مستوردة &rlm;ولديه بطاقة ائتمانية بلاتينية...
Maybe he's a trust fund kid.
&rlm;ربما ترك &rlm;له والداه صندوقاً ائتمانياً وهو صبي.
This place is a dump!
&rlm;هذا المكان قذر!
Hush, Genta!
&rlm;اصمت يا "جنتا"!
It may not look like much, but home is where you make it.
&rlm;قد لا يبدو رائعاً، لكن المنزل &rlm;هو المكان الذي تجعله منزلك.
I'll park the car, so you go on inside.
&rlm;سأصف السيارة، لذا ادخلوا.
Okay!
&rlm;حسناً!
Apartment #3 SHIGA
&rlm;- "شقة 3، (شيغا)" &rlm;- إنه الـ"هاوكن" حقاً!
The grip really is shiny and gold!
&rlm;المقبض لامع وذهبي حقاً!
- It's so pretty... - Awesome!
&rlm;- إنه جميل جداً... &rlm;- مذهل!
Sheesh...
&rlm;تباً...
It's full of junk food, instant noodles and mini-mart bento boxes.
&rlm;إنه مليء بالوجبات السريعة والمعكرونة &rlm;سريعة التحضير وعلب طعام السوق الصغير.
Their diet is on display here.
&rlm;نظامهم الغذائي معروض هنا.
- Hey, Haibara. - What?
&rlm;- "هايبارا". &rlm;- ماذا؟
Did you smell something?
&rlm;هل شممت شيئاً؟
Not really.
&rlm;ليس حقاً.
I don't think there's any kitchen garbage in here.
&rlm;لا أعتقد أن هناك قمامة مطبخ هنا.
No, in the hall before we came in.
&rlm;كلا، في الردهة قبل أن ندخل.
No, I didn't notice anything.
&rlm;كلا، لم ألحظ شيئاً.
You didn't?
&rlm;لم تفعلي؟
Hey, where do you get off poking around someone's home?
&rlm;متى ستتوقف عن العبث بمنزل الناس؟
Tell me something, Noriya...
&rlm;أخبرني شيئاً يا "نوريا"...
Did your brother just move here?
&rlm;هل انتقل شقيقك هنا للتو؟
No, it was about a month ago.
&rlm;كلا، منذ حوالي شهر.
Before summer vacation, he lived in the same condo building as my folks.
&rlm;قبل العطلة الصيفية، كان يعيش &rlm;بنفس مبنى شقق والدي.
And Toshinari isn't my brother. He's my cousin.
&rlm;و"توشيناري" ليس أخي. &rlm;إنه ابن خالتي.
He's the son of my mom's older sister.
&rlm;هو ابن الأخت الكبرى لأمي.
My dad is on an overseas business trip right now,
&rlm;أبي برحلة عمل بالخارج الآن.
and Mom has left for a week to take care of him,
&rlm;ورحلت أمي لأسبوع للاعتناء به.
so I'm staying here with Toshinari while she's away.
&rlm;لذا أنا باق هنا مع "توشيناري" &rlm;بينما هي بالخارج.
You're staying here for a week?
&rlm;ستقيم هنا أسبوعاً؟
Yeah. Plus, Mom asked me to do something for her.
&rlm;أجل. بالإضافة لذلك، طلبت أمي مني &rlm;أن أفعل شيئاً لها.
Toshinari's big sister died in a traffic accident six months ago.
&rlm;توفيت أخت "توشيناري" الكبرى بحادث &rlm;مروري منذ 6 أشهر.
He's been really sad ever since,
&rlm;كان حزيناً حقاً منذ ذلك الحين.
so Mom asked me to stay with him and cheer him up.
&rlm;لذا طلبت أمي مني البقاء معه والترويح عنه.
Then he was laying those flowers at the spot where she died...
&rlm;إذن كان يضع تلك الزهور &rlm;بالمكان الذي ماتت به...
Oh, right! I got him to show me some pictures of her earlier!
&rlm;صحيح! جعلته يريني بعضاً &rlm;من صورها بوقت سابق.
She was really nice. She used to take me camping all the time.
&rlm;كانت لطيفة حقاً. كانت تأخذني &rlm;للتخييم دائماً.
Huh? Were there this many pictures before?
&rlm;كان هناك الكثير من الصور من قبل.
Can I see?
&rlm;أيمكنني أن أرى؟
Sure.
&rlm;بالتأكيد.
That's strange. She isn't looking into the camera in any of these last ones.
&rlm;هذا غريب. لا تنظر لآلة التصوير &rlm;بأي من هذه الصور الأخيرة.
And what are these? There are little holes in the tops of the pictures.
&rlm;وما هذا؟ هناك ثقوب صغيرة بقمم الصور.
Th-That was Toshinari!
&rlm;كان... هذا "توشيناري"! &rlm;الردهة... لا تقل لي...
It was coming from apartment #4?
&rlm;كانت آتية من الشقة رقم 4؟
I knew it, that smell was...
&rlm;كنت متأكداً، كانت تلك الرائحة...
Conan?
&rlm;"كونان"؟
What is it?
&rlm;ما الأمر؟
The rest of you, stay back!
&rlm;بقيتكم، ابقوا بعيداً!
Haibara, call the police. Tell them someone has died here.
&rlm;"هايبارا"، اتصلي بالشرطة. &rlm;أخبريهم أن شخصاً ما مات هنا.
On it.
&rlm;حسناً.
What's that?
&rlm;ما هذا؟
The pictures pinned up on this cork board...
&rlm;الصور المعلقة على لوح الفلين هذا...
The pictures and the sun-bleached areas don't quite line up.
&rlm;الصور والمناطق المبيضة بالشمس &rlm;ليست مصطفة بشكل تام.
And it's not just one or two of them.
&rlm;وليست مجرد صورة أو صورتين منهم.
What could cause that?
&rlm;ما الذي يمكن أن يتسبب في هذا؟
She isn't looking into the camera...
&rlm;لا تنظر لآلة التصوير...
There are little holes in the tops of the pictures...
&rlm;هناك ثقوب صغيرة بقمم الصور...
I don't believe it.
&rlm;لا أصدق هذا.
The culprit who did this is...
&rlm;المجرم الذي فعل هذا هو...
It can't be...
&rlm;مستحيل...
I have to say,
&rlm;يجب القول.
I had no idea things had progressed so far with those two.
&rlm;لم يكن لدي أي فكرة أن الأمور &rlm;تطورت لهذا الحد مع هذين الاثنين.
They're gonna get hitched for sure now.
&rlm;سيتزوجان بالتأكيد الآن.
Things are gonna get dangerous for Takagi, though.
&rlm;ستصبح الأمور خطيرة بالنسبة &rlm;لـ"تاكاغي" الآن رغم هذا.
Hm? Dangerous how?
&rlm;كيف ستكون خطيرة؟
Imagine what'll happen when the detectives find out.
&rlm;تخيلي ما سيحدث حين يكتشف المحققون.
Oh, you have a point.
&rlm;نقطة سديدة.
Detective Satou has a big fan club.
&rlm;لدي المحققة "ساتو" الكثير من المعجبين.
- He's in trouble. Seriously. - He sure is.
&rlm;- إنه في ورطة. جدياً. &rlm;- إنه كذلك بالتأكيد.
In serious trouble.
&rlm;في ورطة كبيرة.
Um... Yumi?
&rlm;"يومي"؟
Your mouth is saying one thing, but your face is saying another.
&rlm;فمك يقول شيئاً لكن وجهك يقول شيئاً آخر.
The victim is Hiroto Yasutomi. Age 31, job hopper.
&rlm;الضحية هو "هيروتو ياسوتومي". &rlm;العمر 31 عاماً، يغير عمله كثيراً.
Forensics puts estimated time of death
&rlm;حدد الطب الشرعي وقت الوفاة التقريبي
sometime between 7:00 and 9:00 last night.
&rlm;ما بين السابعة والتاسعة الليلة الماضية.
Repeated stabbings to the chest and abdomen, huh?
&rlm;طعن متكرر بالصدر والبطن؟
Then you were the first person to find the body?
&rlm;إذن كنت أول من عثر على الجثة؟
You're Toshinari Shiga, the next-door neighbor?
&rlm;أنت "توشيناري شيغا"، الجار المجاور؟
Yes.
&rlm;أجل.
I had parked my car in the lot,
&rlm;صففت سيارتي بموقف السيارات.
and when I was going to my own apartment,
&rlm;وحين كنت ذاهباً لشقتي.
I noticed a strange smell coming from this one.
&rlm;لاحظت رائحة غريبة قادمة من هذه الشقة.
The door was unlocked, so I let myself in. That's when I found him like this.
&rlm;كان الباب مفتوحاً، لذا دخلت. &rlm;حينها وجدته هكذا.
I shouted in surprise, and that's when this boy,
&rlm;صرخت من المفاجأة وحينها هذا الصبي.
a friend of my cousin Noriya's, barged in.
&rlm;صديق ابن خالتي "نوريا"، دخل مسرعاً.
Conan?
&rlm;"كونان"؟
Then the girl who reported the body was...
&rlm;إذن الفتاة التي أبلغت عن الجثة كانت...
Me.
&rlm;أنا.
We all came over to hang out at Noriya's cousin's place today.
&rlm;أتينا جميعاً لقضاء الوقت بمنزل قريب &rlm;"نوريا" اليوم.
I have to say, you're every bit the angel of death that Mr. Mouri is.
&rlm;لابد من القول، أنت بكل الطرق ملك الموت &rlm;الذي يقول عليه السيد "موري".
I keep finding you at murder scenes.
&rlm;أستمر بالعثور عليك بمسرح الجرائم.
G-Gosh, you two sure arrived at the scene quickly.
&rlm;يا إلهي! وصلتما أنتما الاثنان &rlm;لمكان الحادث بسرعة.
We got a tip that an employee at a nearby florist's looked like a wanted suspect.
&rlm;حصلنا على معلومة أن موظف بمتجر بيع زهور &rlm;قريب يشبه أحد المشتبه بهم المطلوبين.
It turned out to be a false alarm, though.
&rlm;اتضحت أنها معلومة خاطئة رغم هذا.
We happened to be in the neighborhood, so we caught the case.
&rlm;تصادف وجودنا بالحي، &rlm;لذا استلمنا القضية.
If Takagi hadn't been whispering with that employee about flowers,
&rlm;إن لم يهمس "تاكاغي" مع هذا الموظف &rlm;عن الزهور.
we could have gone straight back.
&rlm;لعدنا مباشرة.
We were still in the area because we were eating lunch!
&rlm;كنا لا نزال بالمنطقة &rlm;لأننا كنا نتناول الغداء.
You were talking about flowers?
&rlm;كنت تتحدث عن الزهور؟
Are you gonna give some to somebody?
&rlm;هل ستعطي بعضاً منها لشخص ما؟
If it was to Det. Satou, he wouldn't have been whispering about it!
&rlm;إن كانت للمحققة "ساتو"، لما همس بشأنها!
He must be cheating. You think so, too?
&rlm;لابد أنه يخونها.
I-I am not!
&rlm;لا أفعل!
To get back on track...
&rlm;للعودة للمسار الصحيح...
If he died between 7:00 and 9:00 last night,
&rlm;إن مات بين السابعة والتاسعة &rlm;الليلة الماضية.
why don't you ask Noriya and Toshinari about it?
&rlm;فلماذا لا تسألا "نوريا" و"توشيناري" &rlm;عن هذا؟
They were next door, so they might have heard strange sounds or something.
&rlm;كانا بالشقة المجاورة، لذا ربما &rlm;سمعا أصواتاً غريبة أو شيئاً.
During those hours last night, I was watching TV with Toshinari!
&rlm;خلال تلك الساعات الليلة الماضية، &rlm;كنت أشاهد التلفاز مع "توشيناري"!
The Kamen Yaiba movie was on.
&rlm;كان يعرض فيلم "كامين يابا".
I watched that, too!
&rlm;شاهدته أيضاً!
Me, too! Wasn't it awesome?!
&rlm;وأنا أيضاً، ألم يكن رائعاً؟
It was on from 7:00 to 9:00 for its first TV broadcast!
&rlm;كان من السابعة للتاسعة &rlm;بأول عرض تلفزيوني له!
You didn't hear any strange sounds or moaning while it was on?
&rlm;ألم تسمع أي أصوات غريبة أو أنين &rlm;بينما يعرض؟
Yeah! During the movie, our neighbor banged on the door
&rlm;أجل! خلال الفيلم، طرق جارنا على الباب.
and yelled at us to turn it down.
&rlm;وصاح بنا لخفض الصوت.
Around what time was that?
&rlm;كم كان الوقت تقريباً؟
I think it must have been around 7:30.
&rlm;أعتقد أنها كانت حوالي بالسابعة ونصف
I apologized through the door and turned down the volume.
&rlm;اعتذرت من خلال الباب وخفضت الصوت.
Which means that Mr. Yasutomi was still alive at that time.
&rlm;وهو ما يعني أن السيد "ياسوتومي" &rlm;كان لا يزال على قيد الحياة بذلك الوقت.
Did you hear anything strange after that?
&rlm;هل سمعت أي شيء غريب بعد ذلك؟
Well... Kamen Yaiba is one of those superhero shows,
&rlm;حسناً... "كامين يابا" هو أحد &rlm;برامج الأبطال الخارقين تلك.
so there was a lot of screaming and explosions.
&rlm;لذا كان هناك الكثير من &rlm;الصراخ والانفجارات.
Even if there had been any strange noises, I might not have noticed.
&rlm;حتى لو كان هناك أي ضوضاء غريبة، &rlm;فلماذا لاحظت؟
Besides, his body was found by his kitchen sink,
&rlm;بالإضافة لذلك، عثر على جثته &rlm;بجانب مغسلة المطبخ.
which is two rooms away from where we were watching TV.
&rlm;وهو على بعد غرفتين من حيث &rlm;كنا نشاهد التلفاز.
Come to think of it, I saw him at the mini-mart yesterday evening.
&rlm;تذكرت للتو، رأيته في السوق المركزي الصغير &rlm;مساء أمس.
Around what time?
&rlm;بأي وقت تقريباً؟
Well, it was when we were buying bento boxes for dinner.
&rlm;حسناً، كان حين كنا نشتري علب الطعام &rlm;للعشاء.
I remember being worried about their expiration date
&rlm;أتذكر شعوري بالقلق من تاريخ &rlm;انتهاء صلاحيتهم
and asking Noriya what day it was.
&rlm;وسؤال "نوريا" عن تاريخ اليوم.
You asked a child what the date was?
&rlm;سألت طفلاً عن التاريخ؟
Yeah! I was holding the shopping basket.
&rlm;أجل! كنت أحمل سلة التسوق.
It had a newspaper in it that we were going to buy.
&rlm;كان بها صحيفة سنشتريها.
I told him that "August 13th" was written on it.
&rlm;أخبرته أن مكتوب عليها 13 أغسطس.
I said that was the day that the Kamen Yaiba movie was gonna be on TV.
&rlm;قلت إنه يوم عرض فيلم "كامن يابا" &rlm;بالتلفاز.
If it was the 13th, that means it was yesterday.
&rlm;إن كان 13، هذا يعني أنه كان أمس.
When you saw him, was Mr. Yasutomi with anyone?
&rlm;حين رأيته، هل كان السيد "ياسوتومي" &rlm;مع أي شخص؟
No, I think he was by himself.
&rlm;كلا، أعتقد أنه كان بمفرده.
Say, Noriya... Did Toshinari get up to go to the bathroom or anything
&rlm;قل لي يا "نوريا"... هل ذهب"توشيناري" &rlm;للحمام أو أي شيء
while you were watching the movie?
&rlm;بينما كنت تشاهد الفيلم؟
No, I was sitting against him the whole time.
&rlm;كلا، كنت جالساً بجانبه طوال الوقت.
What did you do after it was over?
&rlm;ماذا فعلتما بعد انتهائه؟
It ended before 9:00, right?
&rlm;انتهى قبل التاسعة صحيح؟
Yeah! I went to pee right after it ended and then I went back to playing my game.
&rlm;أجل. ذهبت للتبول بعد انتهائه مباشرة &rlm;ثم عدت للعب لعبتي.
"Went back to"? You were playing it before the movie, too?
&rlm;"عدت"؟ هل كنت تلعبها قبل الفيلم أيضاً؟
Yeah, I played from the time we got back from the store until the movie started.
&rlm;أجل، لعبت من وقت عودتنا من المتجر &rlm;حتى بدأ الفيلم.
Toshinari looked at his watch and said,
&rlm;نظر "توشيناري" لساعته وقال
"Oh, no! It's already 7:00!
&rlm;"كلا! إنها السابعة بالفعل!
The movie's starting, so we'd better save our game."
&rlm;سيبدأ الفيلم، لذا من الأفضل حفظ لعبتنا." &rlm;حفظناها سريعاً جداً وأعدناه للكابل.
We did it just in time, because the movie had just started!
&rlm;قمنا بالأمر بالوقت المناسب تماماً، &rlm;لأن الفيلم كان قد بدأ للتو.
While you were in the bathroom after the movie ended,
&rlm;بينما كنت في الحمام بعد انتهاء الفيلم.
Toshinari didn't leave the apartment?
&rlm;ألم يترك "توشيناري" الشقة؟
Nope, he asked me what kind of snacks I wanted from outside the bathroom door.
&rlm;كلا، سألني ما نوع الوجبات الخفيفة &rlm;التي أريدها من خارج باب الحمام.
Then you played your game together all evening after that?
&rlm;ثم لعبتما لعبتكما معاً طوال المساء &rlm;بعد ذلك؟
That's right! We played until pretty late,
&rlm;هذا صحيح. لعبنا لوقت متأخر جداً.
and then after I got up early and played some more,
&rlm;ثم بعد أن استيقظت مبكراً &rlm;ولعبت مجدداً.
I went to the store with Toshinari to go buy breakfast.
&rlm;ذهبت للمتجر مع "توشيناري" لشراء الإفطار.
After that, I played until around noon or so.
&rlm;بعد ذلك، لعبت حتى الظهر تقريباً
Then I got tired, so I took a nap.
&rlm;ثم شعرت بالتعب فنمت القيلولة.
After I woke up, I played some more,
&rlm;بعد أن استيقظت، لعبت مجدداً.
and then I got hungry, so we went to the store.
&rlm;وبعد ذلك شعرت بالجوع فذهبت للمتجر.
And that's when I ran into you guys! Talk about gaming night and day!
&rlm;وحينها التقيت بكم مصادفة!
That's why your rank was so high!
&rlm;لهذا ترتيبك مرتفع جداً!
I'm jealous!
&rlm;أشعر بالغيرة!
What about lunch, then?
&rlm;ماذا عن الغداء إذن؟
Oh, I'd been snacking all day, so I wasn't hungry at all.
&rlm;كنت أتناول وجبات خفيفة طوال اليوم، &rlm;لذا لم أشعر بالجوع مطلقاً.
Snacking and gaming all day!
&rlm;تتناول وجبات خفيفة وتلعب طوال اليوم!
-That's so great! -I'd call that Heaven!
&rlm;- هذا رائع جداً! &rlm;- هذا ما أسميه النعيم!
Don't follow his example.
&rlm;لا تحذوا حذوه.
So you were with Toshinari all day again today?
&rlm;إذن هل كنت مع "توشيناري" طوال اليوم &rlm;مجدداً اليوم؟
After we ate breakfast, he said he had an errand to run,
&rlm;بعد أن تناولنا الإفطار، قال إن &rlm;لديه مهمة يجب أن يقوم بها.
so I should play my game while he was out.
&rlm;لذا يجب أن ألعب لعبتني بينما هو بالخارج.
He didn't want the man next door to get mad at us again,
&rlm;لم يرد أن يغضب جارنا منا مجدداً.
so he said to play with headphones on.
&rlm;لذا قال لي أن ألعب وأنا أضع السماعات.
When was that?
&rlm;متى كان هذا؟
Let me think...
&rlm;دعني أفكر...
It was around 6 o'clock when we went to the store to buy breakfast,
&rlm;كانت حوالي الساعة السادسة حين &rlm;ذهبنا للمتجر لشراء الإفطار.
and that was right after we came home and ate it,
&rlm;وكان هذا بعد عودتنا للمنزل &rlm;وتناوله مباشرة.
so I guess that was around 7:00.
&rlm;إذن أعتقد أنها كانت حوالي السابعة.
The clock behind the cashier at the store said it was just after 6:00.
&rlm;الساعة خلف أمين الصندوق بالمتجر &rlm;كانت تشير لبعد السادسة بقليل.
What? Do you suspect the brother?
&rlm;ماذا؟ هل تشك بالأخ؟
Excuse me...
&rlm;عفواً...
Would you mind if we went back to my apartment?
&rlm;هل تمانع إن عدنا لشقتي؟
I'd rather not make these kids hang around a dead body.
&rlm;أفضل عدم تواجد هؤلاء الأطفال &rlm;بجانب جثة هامدة.
Good point.
&rlm;وجهة نظر سديدة.
Just to rule you out, I'd like to go through your garbage and things.
&rlm;لمجرد إستبعادك من دائرة الاشتباه، &rlm;أود البحث في قمامتك وأشياء.
-Is that all right? -Sure, that's fine.
&rlm;- هل أنت موافق؟ &rlm;- بالتأكيد، لا بأس.
Hey, I know you!
&rlm;مهلاً، أعرفك!
You weren't at the florist's earlier, were you?
&rlm;كنت بمتجر الزهور بوقت سابق، صحيح؟
Yes, I bought some flowers.
&rlm;أجل، اشتريت بعضاً من الزهور.
I thought so!
&rlm;ظننت ذلك.
When I asked what kind of flowers to give someone when a wish comes true,
&rlm;حين سألت ما نوع الزهور التي تعطيها &rlm;لشخص حين تتحقق أمنية.
the guy there said, "How about a bouquet of false dragonheads
&rlm;قال الرجل هناك "ماذا عن باقة &rlm;(فولس دراغونهيد)
like that man just bought?"
&rlm;مثل التي اشتراها هذا الرجل للتو؟"
I caught a glimpse of you just as you were leaving.
&rlm;لمحتك بينما كنت ترحل.
So you just got some good news, Detective Takagi?
&rlm;إذن تلقيت للتو أخبار جيدة &rlm;أيها المحقق "تاكاغي"؟
Did you win a prize on your ice cream stick?
&rlm;هل فزت بجائزة على عصا مثلجاتك؟
C'mon, tell us!
&rlm;هيا، أخبرنا!
Uh, well... Help me out here!
&rlm;حسناً... ساعديني هنا!
Huh? Why?
&rlm;لماذا؟
I said I'd do right by you, didn't I?
&rlm;قلت إنني سأعاملك معاملة جيدة، ألم أفعل؟
Oh, that.
&rlm;هذا.
Well, you're partly to blame for my little situation.
&rlm;حسناً، تتحمل جزءاً من اللوم على وضعي.
I'd say it's only natural that you man up and do the right thing.
&rlm;لقلت إنه من الطبيعي أن تتشجع &rlm;وتقوم بالصواب.
Y-You have a point.
&rlm;وجهة نظر جيدة.
That's the flower you bought?
&rlm;هل هذه هي الزهرة التي جلبتها؟
Yes.
&rlm;أجل.
In that case,
&rlm;بهذه الحالة.
did you also have some kind of wish come true?
&rlm;هل كان لديك أيضاً رغبة تحققت؟
Y-Yes... I suppose.
&rlm;أجل... أعتقد.
Mr. Shiga. Shall we go to your apartment, then?
&rlm;سيد "شيغا"، هل نذهب لشقتك إذن؟
S-Sure...
&rlm;بالتأكيد...
Say, Detective Takagi.
&rlm;قل لي أيها المحقق "تاكاغي".
What is it, Conan?
&rlm;ما الأمر يا "كونان"؟
There's something I'd like you to find out for me.
&rlm;هناك شيء أود منك أن تعرفه من أجلي.
Toshinari placed those flowers by the road in front of that florist's,
&rlm;وضع "توشيناري" تلك الزهور على &rlm;الطريق أمام متجر الزهور.
so I was wondering if there had been an accident there.
&rlm;لذا كنت أتساءل إن كان وقع حادث هناك.
- Oh, he did? - Come on. Quit dawdling, Takagi.
&rlm;- فعل ذلك؟ &rlm;- بربك، توقف عن تضييع الوقت يا "تاكاغي".
S-Sure...
&rlm;بالتأكيد...
- Get a move on! - Should you be exerting yourself, Satou?
&rlm;- امضي قدماً! &rlm;- لا يجب أن ترهقي نفسك يا "ساتو"!
You should be taking it easy!
&rlm;يجب أن تستريحي.
He's probably the one who murdered Mr. Yasutomi.
&rlm;هو غالباً من قتل السيد "ياسوتومي".
It was Toshinari Shiga, I'm sure of it.
&rlm;كان "توشيناري شيغا"، أنا متأكد من ذلك.
And the murder weapon is probably in...
&rlm;وسلاح الجريمة غالباً في...
But the problem is his alibi.
&rlm;لكن المشكلة هي حجة غيابه.
At the time of the murder, 7:00 to 9:00 on the evening of August 13th,
&rlm;بوقت وقوع الجريمة، من السابعة إلى التاسعة &rlm;مساء 13 أغسطس.
he was right next to Noriya the whole time.
&rlm;كان بجانب "نوريا" طوال الوقت.
Damn it...
&rlm;اللعنة...
How the hell did you murder Mr. Yasutomi?
&rlm;كيف قتلت السيد "ياسوتومي" بحق الجحيم؟
Well?
&rlm;حسناً؟
Takagi? Did you get some good news today, then?
&rlm;"تاكاغي"؟ هل تلقيت أخباراً سعيدة اليوم &rlm;إذن؟